Jacob A Feitler - Full Stack Web Developer

Detroit, Michigan 1-216-403-3629 jfeitler@gmail.com www.jacobfeitler.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/jacobaf GitHub: github.com/jacob-af

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with a solid background in collaboration, teamwork, and achieving goals from a successful career in hospitality. I prioritize best practices and always put the user's needs first. I'm excited to join a team where we can learn, grow, and create great web experiences together, from front to back.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, TypeScript, CSS3, HTML5, Python3 **Applications**: GitHub, VSCode, Postman, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Tools: React, Redux, Next.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Handlebars, Node, Express,

Nest.js, Sequelize, Prisma, GraphQL

PROJECTS

Pocket Bar Book

Summary: Full stack cocktail recipe creation, storage, and sharing

Role: Sole Developer

Tools: TypeScript, Postgres, Nest.js, Prisma, GraphQL, Apollo, Next.js, Next-Auth, Next-

PWA, Tailwind

Live Demo: www.pocketbarbook.com

Frontend Repo: github.com/jacob-af/pocket-front Backend Repo: github.com/jacob-af/pocket-server

Pet Pandemonium

Summary: Full Stack pet-themed PVP 'battleship' style game with chat

Role: React API Layer, Game Logic, Socket implementation Tools: React, Socket.io, Howler, Bootstrap, Axios, MongoDB

Live Demo: pet-pandemonium.onrender.com

GitHub Repo: github.com/jacob-af/pet-pandemonium

Puppy Party Planner

Summary: Filter weather conditions for optimal dog-park outings

Role: Responsive UI and jQuery display logic Tools: HTML, CSS, Materialize.css, jQuery/AJAX Live Demo: jacobfeitler.com/Puppy-Party-Planner/ GitHub Repo: github.com/jaortisi6/Puppy-Party-Planner

SELECTED WORK EXPERIENCE

Coding Data Annotator, Data Annotation Tech 01/2024 - Present

Specialized in the use of Generative AI to develop, review, correct, and elucidate code across multiple programming languages including JavaScript, Python, and SQL.

Enhanced data annotation tools and methodologies, improving coding efficiency and accuracy.

Collaborated in a tech-driven environment, honing problem-solving and technical troubleshooting skills.

Bar Manager, Oak & Reel / The Upright 10/2020 - 10/2023

Led cocktail creation and event planning at a modern Italian restaurant under the guidance of a Michelin-starred chef.

Managed cost analysis and inventory control, applying analytical skills that are essential for backend web development and database management.

Trained and managed a diverse team, strengthening leadership and project management skills.

Beverage Director, The Whitney 8/2019 - 10/2020

Oversaw beverage selection and inventory for a high-end service environment, focusing on meticulous detail and premium service quality.

Applied rigorous costing and management practices, fostering a strong foundation in data analysis and financial oversight.

Assistant Bar Manager, The Sugar House 9/2017 - 7/2019

Developed a varied cocktail menu, requiring creative solution-finding and adherence to high standards, parallel to developing user-centric web applications.

Managed inventory and mastered a repertoire of over 100 cocktails, demonstrating an ability to handle extensive datasets, a skill useful for managing large-scale web projects.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate 9/2020-5/2021
Michigan State University

Studies in Mechanical Engineering 1/2008-12/2009
Cleveland State University

Studies in Mathematics and Music Theory 9/2000-12/2003 University of California, Santa Cruz